HANNAH ROSE

Senior Unity Programmer

she/her
hannaesthetic.r@gmail.com
Based in Newcastle-upon-Tyne, UK

ABOUT

Hi!

I'm Hannah Rose, a Senior Unity Programmer with 8 years professional experience, 5 of which have been in games. I've worked both freelance and remote, on games which have launched on PC, VR, consoles and mobile. I've the small team experience to wear many hats and pick up any part of a project. I'm very focused on communication, catching issues before they happen and sharing my knowledge with the team. I'm particularly fond of shader and tools focused tasks, especially when I'm making them for an artist or designer to play with.

Very keen on information sharing, I've mentored several people and run several groups to encourage inexperienced game developers to get their first steps making small games for fun.

I've got a list of some of the projects I've worked on professionally **here, on my portfolio**. I'm also a long term hobbyist developer, with a number of tiny, silly, and entirely financially unviable games and toys available on **my itch page**.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Programmer, Senior Programmer — Mike Bithell Games

JULY 2020 - PRESENT

Joined as a freelancer, progressed to full time senior developer. Introduced source control practices, set up biweekly "tools clinics" to encourage non-programmers to share any issues they may have in the hopes a tool could help them, established a culture of team members quietly sitting in on meetings for other departments for better clarity between teams. Serve as the bridge between programming and art teams, participating in most of the art meetings to catch issues with tooling, shaders, source control that they wouldn't think to raise as issues.

UNANNOUNCED PROJECT — APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

Experimented with proc-gen city generation during pre-production. Joined the project fully after the game's vertical slice was completed, to pick up for a developer leaving the team. Wrote major refactors on several of the game's features, made level design tools and effects for the art team, and added level design features such as populating encounters, triggering events, and serializing game state.

TRON IDENTITY (PC, SWITCH) — JULY 2021 - APRIL 2023

Visually focused narrative game. Joined the project after pre-production and served as the only programmer for most of its lifetime, writing most of its systems. Main focuses were: narrative system, debug tools, VFX, tooling to speed up art and design for the creative director.

ARCSMITH (OCULUS QUEST 1 & 2) — APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

Story driven puzzle game about building contraptions in VR. Joined after pre-production as the main programmer. Due to long build times and poor debug features when testing in VR, made the game entirely playable in editor. Large focus on bugfixing, optimisation, and cutscenes.

Freelance Programmer — Spooky Doorway

OCTOBER 2019 - AUGUST 2020

Freelance developer. Initially worked on adapting the studio's narrative engine from a point and click game to a 3D adventure game, also to build the character controller and puzzle mechanics. Rewrote the save system and achievement tracking systems on the studio's previously released title The Darkside Detective, and running migrations that would avoid any lost data. Brought all these change's into the game's sequel, A Fumble In The Dark. Abstracted many of the game's systems for saves, controls, and bootup to prepare for cross platform release. Created tools to automate many of the more narrative design tasks. Did shader work for a prototype heavy stylised game Eldritch House.

Unity Developer — Weather Factory

JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2019

Primary developer during pre-production of BOOK OF HOURS. Brought into a team which previously had no full time programmers, brought in source control, code reviews, and established content pipelines for the company as it scaled up. Prototyped many of the game's core systems and visuals, in preparation for the game's Kickstarter campaign. Wrote tools to allow the creative director to do all writing and add assets without having to touch the code.

Junior Developer — Immersive Studios

OCTOBER 2018 - MAY 2019

Developer at a VR/AR studio, primarily working in Unity, with some web development. Developed VR, AR, 360 video experiences, web landing pages, mobile apps. Learned shader development in time between projects, as it was a blindspot in the team which the artists needed covered. Brought in source control practices, teaching and assisting the other developers to onboard them to these new practices.

Course Developer — Code Kingdoms

JUNE 2015 - JUNE 2018

A company which sought to teach children aged 8-14 how to program by teaching them to make games. I was in charge of creating the entire curriculum of over 60 different Minecraft mods and Roblox games. This included planning a full curriculum, designing and building games to cover individual lessons, scriptwriting for the accompanying video, creating visual assets used in the games and videos, and providing live support to students who needed help.

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science — University of Warwick

OCTOBER 2012 - JULY 2015